Okay, we're all over the city council meeting for today's date and time.
Item 2 is public input and unscheduled personal parents is only on the Swiss
two-dusted council on any of the council agenda items.
We're being known item 3 is consent agenda staff is recommending items 4 through 11 for
the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on either of those items that entertain the motion to the
team as recommended, we have a motion and a second.
Second, roll call please.
Orcate.
Worcester.
Lewis.
Hi, so.
Item 12 is to accept or reject proposal reporting submission as a
cure for the breach in fiscal year 2018-19.
One of the outside organizational contracts in this case community crisis center.
Hi, Jill.
Item 2.
The next two agenda item.
First one is Kila.
Kila.
She is with the community crisis center.
We have two outside organizations that need to cure their contracts due to a couple of late
reports.
We've submitted a little bit late.
So, Kila, do we as the first one with community crisis and then it says Kendra, but it's
a lititial remaster, it's with Grand Gate Wraith for fellow Dan.
And are both cured?
You guys are going to decide whether it's cured.
You'll have to vote to accept their proposal.
Which is an effect.
Okay.
Thank you.
And if you want to talk, this is, this Kila, if you want more asking questions.
Well, I guess the question is, are they cured today?
I understand that they weren't filed in a timely manner.
Has everything been filed that was asked for?
Yes.
The contract required that the 10% reduction plan be submitted by January 1st and it was not.
So, both of these need to cure based on that.
And has, but has been filed now?
Yes.
From our perspective, they have done with contract fires now, but again, it is late.
So, we need to have you to approve the cure.
Okay.
And it's clear what the expectation, if there's a future contract that those expectations need to be mapped.
Do we have any more questions on item 12?
Yes.
Do we have a motion to approve the cure?
This is the terminal of makes motion.
And a second?
Sir.
Roll call, please.
Question.
Aye.
For a start.
So.
Aye.
Thank you.
And item 12 similarly is Grand Gateway EDS.
Doing business as Pelavan.
We're negligent in getting that 10% reduction paperwork filed.
And that has been done.
Yes.
And we just need to approve that.
And the organization understands the requirements going forward.
Okay.
Any.
other questions on that? Do we have a motion to approve the QR for that brief? I'll make
that motion. Do we have a set on set? We'll call the police.
So, for Mr. Weston, Lewis, I'm in forget. Thank you, both of us.
Yes, thank you. Adam 14, except to reject Grossman on the prize for Splash Pad as proposed by
construction manager at risk. I don't know if there's city manager to sign the notice
of this issue. You're going to look like Justin.
Now, I was supposed to go ahead with the software back. So, I'm heading out.
Robert Kager is also here in Magna to get any questions regarding Splash Pad.
We received all the bids. We came in with in our budget. So, we're just asking you to
accept the grantee maximum price of the gross maximum price for this project so we can get under
and I apologize that I don't have that number in front of me.
The total contract is 599,797.
That sounds like less than what we're expecting.
Well, it's right there. We will kind of in a little bit under budget.
Once we remove the cut plot, it's like the gross ratio structure.
And, because the donation and the restrooms are paying for out of the capital burden.
Awesome. And the fencing from the donation by the end of the crowd comes in.
Great.
Okay. That's all great news. Do we have a start date?
Okay.
Let's see if we get caught.
What's going on over now? There's a lot of dirt work that's been put down.
There's a lot of in-kind services that we're doing in-house.
And preparing the pad was one of those.
So, we have removed the dirt from the old B&X track and we'll put it at the Splash Pad.
Just reuse that.
We're using it.
Okay.
And so we're still looking at an opening when we're supposed to.
Sometime late following.
We're hoping we're hoping we're hoping we're hoping we're hoping we're hoping we're hoping we're hoping we're going to get in his way.
Good.
It was like a 90-day process.
We start off with, if I thought, correctly.
That was what I was told.
That was the initial intent.
I don't know about getting the water features and things out of the frame of the 2019.
And we have the water inject, the contracts have just been open and not issued.
So we're still shooting this fast as weather will last, but it all depends on a lot of things on the weather.
I just remember a conversation where we thought we would go operational late fall.
That would give us a full either cycle of testing everything.
I think that was our first one.
And we have a delay.
We have to push it back.
So we're hoping for a spring.
That's why we're hustling spring or early summer.
Okay.
The other kind of can't go into fall and then by the time you see it.
else around exactly. Any other questions or concerns on item 14? If not, I would
entertain a motion to approve, to accept the gross minimum price of the CMAR
managed project. I'll make that motion.
I'll say that.
And roll call please.
Lewis, I orchid, Westin, forster, Joseph.
Item 15, or the item that we discussed a few minutes ago as part of the SUA meeting.
I'll go ahead and all the details again. Do we have most to approve of item 15?
Most approve.
Second.
That's picking second.
Who has local speakers?
Westin.
Hi.
Lewis.
Hi, forster, orchid, Joseph.
And item 16, is that also a repeat, robber of the previous item?
Mr. Chairman, there are no other questions on that item.
Item 10, and I'll also do approve item 16.
And second, roll call please.
Fork it, Westin, orster.
I'll leave it, I'll show it.
Item 17, discussion, vote on the SUA meeting.
Finally, it's paying at the Oshkaosh capital for pumper and the latter.
Robert.
In 2010, we purchased the flattering engine at the North Station in 2020, those leads is up.
We established a committee for the truck committee, which consists of legal finance and
the fire department.
We had three options.
We have to report between 24 months and 18 months out of what we'd like to do, and we picked
option number two.
Pay the bloom payment in full and retain the equipment.
We fill out all the lists more options when we're done with what we'd like to do.
The other two options are turning in the equipment and starting a new equipment, or the other
one is that we finance the bloom payment.
And you're up and you're just paying the bloom payment.
Yes.
The interest rate was good, and you know, with the payment off early, that it's more than it is to
pay it on the out, and then when the bloom comes to pay that.
And it's remember right the bloom payment, and it's in the remainder of about 200,000, but it
will be able to plan forward over two fiscal years.
That's what also helps our ability not have to come up with.
So, let's come out of operating funds, right, so that we'll have one proof that we will budget
that we'll probably budget money in the next coming fiscal year, and then we'll let over to the fiscal year
after, and that's what we'll make the limit.
And it's 10 years old now, it's telling a very good condition of assuming the battery is, the engine,
that's what we like to look at the inventory.
Look at the savings.
So, in the training in the end, the 2014, the 2014 and 2018, we've spent all those.
$17,000 on Indian 30.
How much that was maintenance costs that were resetted, included in the lease?
That's included, but we have to pay for this stuff.
We had to replace all the rubbers in the brakes,
and that was almost 4,000 one year.
But we do, we are on a maintenance contract with them for the 10 years.
And maintenance is included, but the cost and the equipment
that you have through place is not.
And we've had they've got a problem sensor on them,
and we've had through place one of those like three times.
And we would...
What's the cost of that failure look?
Well, the 2010 was the first year that they came out with every single electronic.
It didn't mean the main way that we could take them now.
So everything's electronic, and when you have one circuit fail, it may affect six.
So it's just that was the first year that came out with it.
This truck had glitches ever since, but the lighter has gone.
But you think we've worked the glitches out enough to go ahead and make that purchase for the truck?
You know, it's at the three options.
I think this gives us more leverage with either selling an outright or trading it in.
You know, it's got service, you know, it's been service all along by years.
So, you know, we'd like to remember options.
So you think the trade value is significantly more than 200,000.
And that sounds like the math.
Because if it's not, you would just turn it in.
All right?
And so paying 200,000.
That's not just for the engine.
Okay.
You know, that was for both trucks.
So yeah, it's definitely the latter was like one point.
Our seven or 50,000 engine was like 350 to 1.1 million to total.
The latter today is 1.1 by itself.
Okay.
You said you had an engine for about the same.
Then come on to big.
I thought it'd understand.
Well, but you take, you could take.
Oh, so when you're saying the latter, that's one vehicle.
And then you're saying the latter truck.
I thought you were talking about a latter on the truck.
And that's why there's a latter truck which I was in 2011.
And then there's an engine, which is a bumper that is into three.
And both of those were part of the same lease.
So we're two vehicles on the lease.
All right.
That makes more sense.
That's why I think we'll be.
Oh, we thought it was.
It's not a kind of pricey.
Well, if the latter's good, but the motor's not.
You can't take it later on.
We can't take it later on.
We can't take it on another truck.
Yeah.
It's not quite long enough to go across the channel.
So I heard it partly during some time.
And we're too close to the lease.
That makes more sense.
OK.
So your recommendation is to notify them that we're going to...
retain both vehicles and most likely buy out the contract, buy out the balance of the
lease, and then maybe trade the engine in on something later and keep the latter truck.
We sell it outright, whichever's best for us.
And we've met with six truck companies and it depends on, you know, they've all said,
we can sell that for you.
And here says, what do you trade that in?
Well, it's not going to be a good deal because that's been maintained and that gives us those
options.
Yes.
And we think we can do that or doing that, then just trading it in or going out to bed
right now or having to be able to be more competitive for us if we don't just have to say
anything over the years.
And it reminded that when we make a health run, a hospital, a run where we want to call it now
emergency run.
We're not sending the big truck anymore, so we all are at the North, at the North, at the North
and the North.
And the rescue truck will play a game playing the south of the tracks right up here on the
board.
There's our plan for two rescue trucks someday, so we don't have to keep doing that or...
Well, you know, there's talks of possible in one direction when we would be able to play
the house or the ambulance, and we would know when the truck needs to go with it with the
rescue truck and go on.
So, we have a motion to accept staff's recommendation to basically make the final lease payment
and notify them of their intentions or intentions.
I'll make that motion.
We'll have a second.
A second.
One more question.
I asked for a question.
Were you asked for a question?
I worked.
All right.
Thanks Robert.
Eight teams.
Other new business and pausing.
We're going to talk about...
Cherry Zach.
We're going to talk about the two of the year.
My grandson got a student of the month today.
They have a great text to meet.
And how he's trying to call me.
And I was saying I thought we were going to talk about the chase.
are under my eye.
Okay.
Yes.
All right.
So it's no other view business.
Oh, we'll tell you that.
Chase.
Staff reports.
Certainly new factor.
I've turned this down all the way.
I apologize.
Mayor and capital community announcements.
See you later.
We want to talk about three things.
We thought we'd say good chase for labs.
But that's not what everybody's interested in.
And the risk he asked to go first because hers is more good news item than what
she's got to explain why the power keeps going on and then we'll finish up with the chase.
Okay?
That's the anticipation.
We set out last week theifiers for a meeting that we're going to have with retailers in
our landlords in our community.
The new one's going to be a march forward from 536 to 636.
The plan for the new one is to talk with both the retailers in landlords in our community
about why we have to enforce what we like important for our workers to maintain
at a certain level both for a mental development and community health.
And then also talked about the fact that everything that we're enforcing today is not new.
It has not introduced meaning to the ordinances of city code from a co-components or code enforcement
standpoint.
These are all codes that have been adopted by the Civil and Police for a million years now.
It's the approach that was taken and the way that we have started enforcing the codes that are already
on the first.
We'll also take that opportunity to discuss with them more in-depth than the international property
maintenance code which is one of those codes that has been adopted for many years now that
not necessarily enforced.
And that's the code that allows us to enforce maintenance issues on properties.
One of the big next steps that we'll be taking from our co-components standpoint is in your
past we never entered a property unless we were invited by the landlord or the tenant
to command and inspect the property from and help the safety standpoint.
The international property maintenance code allows us to build in and make those inspections without being
invited by the landlord or the tenant.
We haven't had a just cause so it isn't believed that there's unsafe conditions on the inside
of the property.
Then we can request a time, a day in time, with the landlord and the tenant to go in and conduct the inspection.
So that would be our next, this is our opportunity to do that.
You both that we've tell us in the landlords and that we are next.
We've stepped that we take in our enforcement practices as far as our housing conditions
properly.
You're saying retailers that what you mean is sort of a curse.
Real curse.
Yeah.
You want to be saying the locals that I would just not hear anything.
Real curse.
So we sent out about 50 of these flyers and we also sent it to the citywide to try to get the word out.
So it gives me the landlords and the real interest there as you can.
We've probably will be doing another sort of tenants that you'd like to attend.
I think really I think you might have indicated you were going to attend.
So it's not going to be a formal city council meeting, but I think more than anything else,
but I really want to talk to Chris for Chris T on this excuse me, Chris.
Really, Chris real.
But we've been working up to this type of enforcement.
And I think that it's worked very well.
I think it's worked very well because we've kind of gone down at our enforcement over a few years.
And I think Chris will show the numbers of how we've basically brought it back up.
But we're taking it to another level.
Things that we've not done before, the things that are necessary and things that are left by code.
So I think before we jump in with both feet, we wanted everybody to understand what we're trying to accomplish.
Frankly, I think we're hoping to get advocates.
People understand why we're doing that.
Somebody complains, somebody else that might be saying, that was something the city needs to do.
We'll close out the meeting, they're taking me on the community to talk a little bit about building code and then also building flood maps.
We need to make more of it, or maybe we'll turn to our community when we're there, probably maps are changing.
How do you feel the attendance will turn out on us?
I'm hopeful.
I hope that you know, that we'll have good attendance, but we'll see what happens when that time comes.
We're trying to schedule it at a time that we'll be able to catch people right after work that they can just come here and we're trying to keep it at an hour.
That we want that we'll be there as long as there are questions for us to answer.
Because we want it to be helpful if we want it to be a help for our community and help through the score.
We'd also, that Robert will be there from the Department's perspective.
There are any questions because a lot of this ties into life and health safety.
And also ties in the law enforcement.
The police chief to be there too because there is a tie into the lab of data properties and law enforcement.
So we always talk about staff and that if we ever had a tragedy and something that happened in the community,
some of the first questions would be asked, what did the city do something about it?
This is what we need to do. This is why we do use that.
I think Ryan also to answer the question each time, as far as the tendency, each time we've decided to move further into the compliance parts of our paper that we haven't necessarily forced in the past.
We've tried to communicate those well in advance to give people a far away paper.
and understanding it, what they do next steps, this next one is, it's like a pretty big one for our communities that can impact the landlords and our communities.
So we felt like this was a better way to try to communicate that with them.
I hope the meaning is packed.
There's some that don't show up that we know should be out of the contact and don't fight up a great meaning in the style.
I hope so too.
Yes, we had one show up last night thinking that was to be the last step.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Actually, before you Christie, I was going to ask, this is open to those that have rental properties,
and the dealers, correct?
Can community members participate in this as well?
Yeah, anybody interested?
It's not just strictly for those two groups.
Those are the information that we put out is targeted towards those two groups.
Anybody who's interested?
Obviously.
And again, the thing that's not just necessarily to say, this is the wall of the bed.
We're going to have some discussions.
I know the mayor found a selfless Missouri Render Association that landlords kind of band together,
and they can trade information about if you have some people that go from one property to another and trash them.
You might be able to stop that cycle.
I think there are going to be some discussions about things that we as a city might be able to help them out,
especially when it comes to code compliance.
We want to make this something that is a positive that we can get to the end result.
And the realtors we very typically will have realtors indicate to us that they might have been able to sell a property,
but for the properties on the other side of them looking to lap it at it.
And this is trying to get people to start reinvesting in properties in our town as well.
It's a key component of economic development.
Our housing situation of property values, Thailand, the regulatory team, economic development, and future births for our community.
Well, there's nothing worse to have a well-known police chase to help us out.
That's right.
Yes, I was talking about the added.
The city has two feet in the city to come from D.R.D.A. in the red section,
I fly in from the rock dust sub, so I say rock dust sub.
I rock devil of art.
So front layer to the commerce association, the threat there.
When you go outside commerce, the city area is that the station.
There was a section where they were transmission line started down to me.
You have the ice on it and we had to make swing and temperature.
So you have to think of it.
So the, you know, the lines, expanded and then contracted when they got little cold when they did that and then we had a northeast wing and kind of going into 90 degree angle, the phases of the line that's gathered on the transmission line.
So it was actually a base of meat base.
So that's why there would be the faults.
And then the relay would pick up, because the regular would trip out and it would keep the record back to you.
So that's why our power would be out if you counted it would be for 10 seconds.
So what happened today?
Yes sir.
Today's problem was through all of this, we have a, one of our main, that sub, it's subsation number two.
A nickel subsation is going back, so we set it off to get prepared.
But this is the sub station that we're completely replacing is in 1970's sub station.
You know, it's, it's on its last time.
So that's why we had that little light today because the main kicked out.
And so we were working on that.
But I mean, it's, it's, we've got our money for that evidence in 1973.
I think to be exact.
So has, is GRDA taking any permanent steps?
They put lights on their line and they put some other things on it.
They spend all night with it and they put some weights on it too.
So they would wait down better for the man.
So they, they've, they've, you know, got a face, they're going to do some more maintenance on their sub stations.
So I'm just curious, you talk about commerce, substation, commerce doesn't use GRDA, right?
I don't know, but, but Connor, basically, GRDA still has a sub station that they sell power out of there.
If you notice, you know, they have a sign of GRDA, substation, everything.
So we get fed from that sub station on.
Just physically have us be located.
It's a, it's a, it's a, that's what GRDA first it has is a number of sub stations.
So, because we have the free office, what they refer to the one on Steven,
on their right to the big one right there, that's the free office.
And they call them the commerce substation.
Any questions for Tyler?
Well, I just appreciate you guys.
Give that to the conditions.
I think you're getting fit with a lot of the calls.
And I was always out there.
And you're out of the answer, and then I could go work and get warm either.
So I just set them right now.
And answer text from me.
Yeah.
What is going on?
Thanks, Tyler.
Thank you.
So I have a little chase.
All through town.
Dean asked me to, the nurse council and there's been a lot of special ways.
Your language changed.
Still, for a missed me to shop, but I think.
And then just what the case.
Mr. Greenbell and the double grand.
But that's your one and the other three different counties.
Jazz for Newton Mayors, I'll have old on it for about two weeks.
When the officer's first pull-up, he ran right out of the officer's service,
the first one there.
He drove out and tried to hit her to get away there.
He was charged with a looting, bring roadblocks, salt matter,
go to bed with a little weapon.
Unfortunately, training for the open-ended operator.
There are a pair of model counting, and I'll see about my way from her,
see about what I'm doing.
The, you know, we've had a lot of people being critical on a,
and why we didn't crash, and why we didn't.
Now, not in front of the field.
It's strictly prohibited by our policies to be able to do that.
Our policy, which is a clean and actually accredited policy,
it equates down to use of the other force,
especially OECP training on land usage.
And everybody goes to equipment with the wrap room bars to do that.
And I want to have the opportunity to put around an end to the end of the pursuit of reporting.
Our officer did an excellent job, you know, personally,
in trying to cut him off.
And in a pursuit of several roadblocks,
in the video you see a couple of times,
a stop takes were deployed.
They weren't successful in the end.
So they were deployed?
They were assumed that something that I was asking.
They were not successful in the point.
They were two different sets.
And they just weren't successful in the end.
One set that got wrapped up and didn't deploy right.
So it was a time it just didn't work.
And that was nothing else.
It's not like that.
And I had, and I myself was curious when you,
when you were watching and they were going through the field,
why we didn't just nudge the guy I was saying,
but you know,
and I had that question to ask of me.
And my assumption was that they were not trained.
And the things you said,
we're not trained.
I'll be equals only quick.
And the OHPR.
And had we cause that person to run into a tree
and be seriously injured.
That's a good question.
I kind of assumed those things,
but I just have to say it still may be uncomfortable
to see him flying through town.
Absolutely.
I know.
Admittedly, dangerous situation.
And, you know, the whole time you're doing it,
you have to wait, public safety persons.
The other need to get this guy off straight.
And then the offense and the occurs.
It worked.
But at the time, we didn't know he was more than three counties.
That's correct.
When everything started, all we know is he was,
almost a shoplifting, blushing, whatever.
And then...
It's right in the office.
to a problem next level where we continue to turn to the work, Chancing. If you're willing to run
down on for a year, not really going to stop as much to get away, you know, there's nothing
you're really beyond your realm, or to get away. So, your department, despite all that, everything,
you know, it feels that it was just to find chase. Well, you guys do sit down and kind of
a thoughtful analysis of that and a work of two, after the emotions you've kind of settled down
and say, well, there's something different we could have done. Yes. Yeah, we will be briefed
that. First of all, Eric, we can improve and think you're going to do better, and we're trying
to use all these further experiences. You know, some people over at the last part, we did just tell
the work road. That's called a dead block, it's a billy hole. You can't, you have to do it around
hell. It's crazy as that sounds. You sit on TV all the time, it's blocked road. You actually have to do
what I have to do to the go line. That's my block. So, we have a dead block road, which thing about seems
exactly what we can't have a product is the way we're trying to do, but that is long. We'll show introducing
deadly force in a situation that may or may not call for it. Any questions for a chain for comments,
or thoughts? I can't argue with what you said, but I do hope that you guys sit down and once the
emotions have settled, look at it and just ask ourselves, if this exact situation happens again in the
future, is there something that we might do differently to provide protection for our citizens?
Did that get what did it? Did pass by? I know pass by here, correct. Any other questions?
Yes, please, please. Any other questions? With through my yard once.
Nicole, don't remember how we've been with a bull on the road.
Actually, we posted the route of the forest in our first day. Well, no, there's another posting that does show the
route. That's right. We'll try to program all GLCs, that my tracks will be going. We'd see where
we're off to the wall here, when the top of this patch was able to follow it. And from that we took a live track
from the vehicle that the video was from and posted that track from sound. I don't believe
it would work to buy a great score of the most cool. It was going to walk south.
Did anybody go there in my yard now? Was it we down?
the North Rockdale, and then we're buying a school.
That meant being the cars just did, the cop cars.
Police cars perhaps, yeah.
But the suspect, I don't believe it.
I just wondered if there's anything like, I know it's up in the middle.
It's up right there.
I know there's all the tools in here, you know, we put all the schools on the
block down because of that except for the defeated in the college.
Definitely.
There was one in college.
No.
We called all the minor public schools, we use our block-down, and it puts all
schools on the block-down, so there's no kids out during that time, just because of that
hazard.
So we tried to do everything because they're too aware.
Is that something that I mean working there, seeing the
students crossing paths across the street?
Right.
It's right.
I don't know if any of the police department can, because we have a text in, I think,
go to all students at that point.
So you have a long-doubt of all the witnesses that you've been triggered in that scenario.
Or just to alert students, you know.
I mean, so we're saying that.
I know, the way we did with West from Rockdown, South, Amin, down to St. Lawrence, back up,
and back up to Central, I believe back in North Amin, for a rumor, right.
So it was my school twice.
I know, you know, how to vehicle there, I've lived in the street, I think we're part of our
part of the murder scene in the arts, and I have a group of street comes out there, and
then I had a unit said right there, and so I know they were advised, and what protocol they
took at school, I don't know.
No.
Good to know.
So I know they were there.
So that might be something that we, if we have a protocol, we, when we contact all the schools,
we need to see if any of us is on that list all the time.
But if we were informed, I would assume that our police officers on campus should inform
us.
I know the school officers are aware, they're, they're locked, they're, they're, they're
they're, they're turning back to the east or to the west, so I know that they were always aware
of that.
Okay.
Any other questions for the chief or dean?
Somebody works for the Resner Plane Ball, too, and I had, there wasn't an airplane.
I promised I'd love to.
Okay.
Always be, I had their craft, any rows or pilot?
Yeah.
He had just departed from a group, so he did come up here.
He was here.
I did follow the pursuit, there was actually another always be involved, pursuit at the exact same
time.
He broke out, went to it, but he was here for a moment.
How many, how we've probed revolved?
I know several went right past Darbo at a high race.
I blew us off three years.
Three years.
We had always be, my imagination.
May I have a B.I.A. Commerce in the old, and I don't think I'm going to sit in the day
to help while we're around the school?
I know in the video that looks like it ended up, I'm here to hear that house, and it may
have been very near a kid and really tell from the perspective, but they did choose a
part of town to actually have a new run, it was very little population down the
house.
And that's, you know, when we go to that, and then it's to ensure public safety and you
have seen that go bad, seeing car roll because of that, and a lot of property damage
when they do that.
And that's, they get to place that was much off to be basic.
You know, any other questions for the T.D. for D?
Okay.
Thank you.
Anything else, Dean, under city manager communications?
I am 22 this adjourment.
Do we have a motion to adjourn?
Motion?
Second.
Roll call, please.
What's in?
Hi.
Who is I forster?
Or kids?
I should.
We get down there.